

Misaki Koonce

Seattle, WA

415 818 5034

misaki.koonce@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/misaki-koonce

SUMMARY

Japanese-English Professional living in Seattle. I have a diverse background, a degree in Policy Studies, and have worked in Japan, China, and the US.

- Proven leader, mentor, and project manager
- Excellent communication skills and teamwork
- Track record of strong customer and client relations

EDUCATION

Bachelors of Policy Studies, Chuo University

Tokyo, Japan — 2009-2014

Chuo University is a private university and one of the most prestigious Japanese universities, renowned for its college of law and policy studies. The school is known for producing countless Lawyers, Policy Makers, and Business Leaders.

I studied about Environmental Issues and Sustainable Economic Policies while simultaneously working with the nonprofit AIESEC.

EXPERIENCE

Corporate Administrator, SMBC

San Francisco, California - June 2017 - June 2018, 1 year

SMBC, Sumitomo Mitsui Banking Corporation, is one of Japan's top mega banks which is relied on by businesses and clients around the world.

I worked as a Corporate Administrator in the Japanese and Asian Corporate Banking Department. I managed a transaction load that included loans, deposits, Forex, bills bought, and auditor bookkeeping.

- Managed client accounts directly, including that of over five high-profile
 Japanese and Asian companies
- Oversaw over \$7B USD of loans, deposits, Forex, and bills bought transactions; roughly 30% of the entire office's transaction load
- One of only three managing the entire San Francisco corporate branch

Export Promotion, JETRO USA

San Francisco, California - Jan 2017 - June 2017, 6 months

JETRO, the Japan External Trade Organization, is responsible for ensuring native Japanese companies are successful entering American markets.

I worked as an Assistant to the Export Promotion team. We did market research for companies looking to enter the US, giving briefings and connecting them with US distributors and partners.

- Managed over 10 Japanese accounts
- Ran the JETRO booth at GCC Game Conference

Corporate Candidate, Uniqlo Japan

Saitama, Japan — 2014-2015, 1.7 years

Uniqlo is a clothing retailer who started in Japan. They are known for creating the "fast fashion" vertical and now operate in over 10 countries. I came to the company to work as the manager of the largest store in Saitama, Japan.

My role included running the store, driving sales and profitability, managing and coaching team members, and hiring staff. This path leads towards working at the Uniqlo corporate office, a path I've tabled to move to the US with my husband.

- Managed over 90 team members
- Oversaw the largest sales in Saitama history: ¥20M, nearly \$170K
- Hired over 10 staff members and mentored over 20 sales staff

Japanese Sales Manager, Howard Johnson

Ningbo, China — 2011-2012, 1 year

Howard Johnson Plaza Ningbo is a five star hotel in Ningbo, China. The hotel is famous with international guests and was ranked the #6 hotel in China by DaoDao.com, as well as enjoying a spot in TripAdvisor's Top 25 Hotels in China.

For me, working at this hotel represented a chance to use both English and Mandarin on a regular basis, bridging sales and lingual services. Living in Ningbo was a bonus.

- Regularly interpreted Japanese, English, and Mandarin between customers and staff
- Edited English materials and verbal playbooks of the hotels
- Led off-site sales to Japanese and Chinese companies interested in business travel

Head of International Relations Committee, AIESEC

Tokyo, Japan— 2009 - 2012, 3 years

AIESEC, pronounced "aye-sec", is a non-profit organization that specializes in building leaders out of youth. From over 120 countries, AIESEC has sponsored conferences and lead internships for young professionals for over 60 years.

I got involved in AIESEC to learn how international non-profits operate, to lead several conferences, and to contribute to internship programs assisting my alum.

- Worked with international branches in Taiwan, Philippines, and China
- Established and expanded the reach of AIESEC to new local committees in other countries
- Attended both the Asia Pacific Exchange Leadership Development Conference in Vietnam in 2011 and the Induction Conference in Mainland of China in 2011 as a mentor